### Contact

janviermuhawenimana@gmail.c

www.linkedin.com/in/ muhawenimana-janvier (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Software System Analysis Graphic Design Web Design

### Certifications

Certified of achievement completion Python programming workshop

# Muhawenimana janvier

Software Developer Kigali

# Summary

Coordinated the development of pledges management system research, working with COLLEGE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY under the guidance of the staff from RUBAVU District with the support of a Belgian Development agency, ENABLE.

Experienced Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the business supplies and equipment industry. Skilled in User Experience (UX), Software System Analysis, User Interface Design, Databases, Mobile Application development, and Graphic Design. Strong engineering professional

# Experience

**TWIS** 

TWIS Mobile application January 2022 - January 2022 (1 month) Rwanda

TWIS is a technology company equipping primary school students with age-appropriate and culturally relevant stories in Kinyarwanda

I designed the mobile application if Twis which allow

- Parents to buy a play for their children so that their children my read books
- Allow the student to perform tests (evaluation) and provide the report to the parent
- Allow the student to save favorite books for offline use

http://twis.rw/about

University of Rwanda Teacher Recruitment System January 2021 - 2022 (1 year) Rwanda The Teacher Recruitment System will be used by Rwandan citizens who wish to become teachers and trainers in Secondary, primary, pre-primary, TVET, and TTC schools. The application, the selection, the validation of documents, the exam preparation, the exam marking, proctoring or supervising the candidate, marks publication, teacher placement, and teacher claims are the core functionalities of this system. Teacher Recruitment System in Rwanda under the support of Mastercard Foundation

During the development of this system, I was responsive for the proctoring component on Center and where I allow real-time tracking during exams and automate most tasks that should be done by the supervisor in the room and make it harder to cheat

I also designed the home proctoring component where the candidates will be able to perform the exam at their home and the system will minimize the risk of cheating - this component use candidate's computer webcam and their computer's audio and send them to the supervisor in realtime

I developed the authentication part and implemented the option to use 2 step authentication, and access management in the system.

I participated in the system analysis phase and developed the design language of the system with prototypes and mockups

Progress Technologies
Pledges management system research
January 2019 - 2022 (3 years)
Rwanda

"Pledges Management System (PMS): A project that helps districts to manage, monitor, evaluate, automate, and report their tasks (IMIHIGO) in a simplified way". This project has the main objective to Create a Cross-Platform for local leaders in charge of implementing the contracts and the Government to directly plan with the system and report on their achievement with a focus on the planned activities against the corresponding budget. This project has been initiated by the PROGRESS TECHNOLOGIES LTD in partnership with the COLLEGE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY under the guidance of the staff from RUBAVU District with the support of a Belgian Development agency, ENABLE, the project will initially be tested and piloted by RUBAVU district before it is implemented country-wide.

The PWS Africa Team
Programming Workshop for Scientist in Africa
2020 - 2020 (less than a year)

Kigali, Kigali City, Rwanda

#### Rwanda Basic Education Board

Teachers Management Information System (TMIS) Improvement February 2019 - March 2019 (2 months)

Kigali, Kigali City, Rwanda

The Teachers Management Information System is the system developed under the support of UNICEF to be used by the Rwanda Education Board.

The system also provides the DASHBOARD to help the senior management get a quick summary on key indicators including the numbers of public and private schools, the number of public and private teachers for secondary, primary, and pre-primary schools in Rwanda. The TMIS can generate many reports.

During the development (updates) of the system,

- I was assigned to design all the dashboards found in the TMIS.
- re-design the homepage and clothes UI elements
- Documents Validation with the use of Qr codes
- Design the archive component that extracts information from the operational database and organizes/represents them, in order to facilitate the comparison between years.

### SOFTTECK Ltd

Design Mailing service on Umusanzu Wanjye Progect 2019 - 2019 (less than a year)

Kigali, Kigali City, Rwanda

UMUSANZU WANJYE is the Platform used by Citizens to alert the Government on the Management of Public Infrastructure such as WATER, ROADS, BRIDGES, ELECTRICITY by using their mobile phones.

During the development of this system, I worked on the feature that sent emails to emails to the management of the Public Infrastructure

### **ANTARES**

Antares Information system
September 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 4 months)

Gisenyi, Western Province, Rwanda

Designed the Business solution (Information system) for ANTARES

Antares Information management system is a software that helps Antares
company in their dairy operation where
manages the sales of all its products and services,

- The system manage their payments,
- the stock management, keep on track of the products they have in stock, and send alerts once the product out-the stock
- Improve the organization of the products in the warehouse with the use of the mobile application and Qr-code, this makes it easy to find the product and the stock-related information.
- Employee performance, the system evaluates the employee based on the number of sales done by, designs, services offered by,... And provide a clear report of the employee's performance.
- Dashboards: the system represents the information in a clear and summarized way with the use of graphs, tables, and the information can be displayed in realtime, this helps in decision making.
- The system work on the Intranet (interface network) to minimize the cost of the internet.
- Export various reports in different formats

SHAMA SPRL Web Developer August 2017 - August 2017 (1 month) Congo (DRC)

Information system/ web based internal system for SHAMA SPRL ink Company from Republic democratic of Congo

## Education

UNIVERSITY OF RWANDA

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2018)